# Simoni Patil

## **Associate Consultant**

## **CONTACT**

Address

315, Cole Road, Guelph, ON, N1G 3G7

Phone

+1(519) 760-4674 +917405753926

## E-mail

siyopatel423@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/simonipatel-12d1996

## **SKILLS**

Shopify, Shopify 2.0, Liquid, HTML, Bootstrap, Material UI, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Storybook, AJAX, JSON, React, SFCC

## **LANGUAGES**

**English** 

# **SOFTWARES**

- Github Desktop
- **VSCode**
- Sublime
- ClickUp
- Asana
- MS Office

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Shopify: App Development
- Microsoft Certified: Azure **Fundamentals**
- Coursera: Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools
- Infosys Certified JavaScript Programmer
- Infosys Certified Front End Web Developer
- Infosys Certified React Professional

#### **PORTFOLIO**



An ardent IT personnel with exceptional Project Management and Client Interfacing skills. Gained 5+ years of experience in building Shopify stores for clients from different industries and countries. Proficient with HTML, CSS, Ajax, Jquery and Shopify. Looking for a suitable role in a company that can leverage my potential and help me hone my skills.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

2022 Aug -Current Infosys, Pune, India

#### **Associate Consultant**

- **Collaborated on Salesforce Commerce Cloud projects** for creating layouts based on Figma designs using HTML and CSS/SCSS and JavaScript.
- Worked as **Team Lead on React JS POC** which includes implementation of UI/UX modules and Storybook JS
- Worked on Shopify and Shopify Plus Stores to create custom functionalities using jQuery, JavaScript, AJAX
- Responsible for working on day-to-day maintenance tasks from Jira

2020 Feb -2021 Nov E2M Solutions, Ahmedabad, India

# Sr. Shopify Developer

- Led the team of four and **provided training** for Shopify to
- Responsible for creating Client Interface for a number of projects using Figma and Adobe XD.
- Creating Proposals/Quotations, project plan, and managing the project until deployment.
- Integrated GA and GTM and performed theme optimization.

2018 May -2020 Jan Cirkle Studio, Surat, India

## Sr. Shopify Developer

- Joined as trainee in Cirkle and was given training for 3 months in Shopify CMS.
- Learned LIQUID, a template language.
- Worked on 50+ Shopify stores and delivered them within tight deadlines

#### A BRIEF SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE

# Premium Brands Services LLC (Oct 2023 - Present) **Role: Front end Developer**

- In this SFCC based website, I was responsible for designing pages on Figma designs and add functionalities using javaScript to provide better user
- Created SEO friendly designs which meets W3C standards.
- Overcame the challenge of optimizing large size ecommerce platform by applying code factoring techniques and LightHouse SEO report.

# Adidas, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (Sept 2023 - Oct 2023) Role: Jr. Front end Developer

- In this SFCC project, I worked on configuring and developing the Business Manager and updated page content.
- Responsible for transferring changes to various environments such as staging and production. Also integrated Currency Pricebook and navigation as per business requirements.

## React UI Component Library POC (July 2023 - Sept 2023) **Role: Team Lead**

- Led the team of 7 folks and helped them creating React components using Material UI.
- Implemented Storybook JS, a frontend workshop for UI development and presented to Pune and Nagpur DC team.
- Submitted Infosys Cobalt Asset for one of the react component.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelors in Computer Engineering**

Gujarat Technological University

GPA: 3.4

2014 Aug - 2018 May